The North Wind and the Sun.
A dispute arose between the North Wind and
the Sun, each claiming that he was
stronger than the other.
At last they agreed to try their powers
upon a traveller, to see which could
soonest strip him of his cloak.
The North Wind had the first try; and,
gathering up all his force for the attack,
he came whirling furiously down upon the
man, and caught up his cloak as though he
would wrest it from him by one single
effort: but the harder he blew,
the more closely the man wrapped it round
himself. Then came the turn of the Sun.
At first he beamed gently upon the
traveller, who soon unclasped his cloak
and walked on with it hanging loosely
about his shoulders: then he shone forth
in his full strength, and the man,
before he had gone many steps,
was glad to throw his cloak right off and
complete his journey more lightly clad.
Persuasion is better than force